expatica.com 2018-01-23

# Privacy policy | Expatica

## Privacy policy

Expatica respects and protects the privacy of our users.

Expatica promises never to sell your personal information without your consent to any third parties. Personal information includes name, e-mail address, postal address and answers to survey questions. Expatica.com does not monitor individual traffic patterns on our site – only aggregate reader behaviour is collected. We use this information only to help us develop Expatica to make your user experience more pleasurable.

## Data collection by Expatica

How do we use cookies?

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We use cookies to help track an individual's movements around Expatica’s websites and monitor the presentation of advertisements. Cookies can be necessary when ordering a product online.

Cookies are not related to any personally identifiable information. They are not used to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie. Advertisers may use cookies on Expatica solely for monitoring and tracking advertisement impressions.

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you are able to set your browser to refuse them. However, doing so may impair the functionality of some parts of the Expatica site.

Use of information

Expatica uses information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience on our sites, whether to provide interactive or personalised elements, or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

Expatica offers voluntary registration, where the user is required to supply a username, password and email address, and must answer mandatory survey questions about age, gender, nationality, postal code. Expatica collects information that users voluntarily provide to enable users to move seamlessly through the website.

We use tracking information to determine which areas of our site users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. Expatica does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

Expatica creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because Expatica doesn’t track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser will never know if a specific user clicked their ad.

Expatica also collects information that users voluntarily provide to send out electronic newsletters. We send our newsletter to subscribers on a regular schedule, and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Users can remove themselves from any of our mailing lists by following the unsubscribe link provided in each email/newsletter, or by unsubscribing in the newsletter subscription area of our website.

Expatica does allow selected advertisers to mail promotions to community members, registrants to Expatica Date and newsletter subscribers, and to include information with mailings and newsletters sent by Expatica. We do not give third parties direct access to your details without your permission. All promotions are pre-approved by Expatica and all mailings are conducted by a reputable third party mail house to ensure the names are not misused. Our users have the option of ‘opting out’ from receiving emails from our partners, if they would prefer not to receive our partner’s promotions. You may change this designation at anytime.

## Data collection by third parties

Expatica allows third parties to collect personally non-identifiable information about a user’s online activities through cookies. This information is related to demographic, behavioural and usage patterns, collectively referred to as preference data. This data reflects users’ interactions with the Expatica website.

How third parties use collected information

Preference data is analysed by third parties to define groups into segments based on factors such as geography, gender, age, interests and online actions. For example, users could be grouped into segments such as males interested in cars or females interested in shopping, or a household with two children looking for real estate. These segments are used by online marketers and advertisers to deliver relevant and specific marketing messages and content to online users.

User choices for opting out of third party data collection

Online users can opt out of third party preference data collection, for online behavioural advertising (OBA), using any of the following methods:

1\. Using ‘Your Online Choices’ opt-out tool provided at <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/opt-out>, users can select the company(s) they want to stop from collecting OBA data. The opt-out tool downloads a browser cookie and will only work if the user’s browser is set to accept third-party cookies.

2\. Changing the computer’s browser settings to block, delete and/or control the use of all third party cookies. Refer to the computer’s web browser’s Help documentation for more information about managing the use of cookies directly through the browser settings.

The opt-out tool and browser cookie management can be specific to each computer and each version and type of browser. If an opt-out cookie is deleted from a browser’s cookie files or if a different computer, browser version and/or browser type is used, the user may need to repeat the opt-out process to stop third-party data collection.

## Community pages

Expatica.com provides message boards for users to post discussions on various topics, events and classified advertisements, where only registered users are permitted to post on the boards. Details provided by users are not used for any other purpose, and contributors to our forums have the option to remain anonymous to other users.

## Expatica Date

Expatica Date is owned and operated by a third-party service, Dating Factory (Tyche Technologies AG, Switzerland). By registering for and/or accessing Expatica Date, you also become a Dating Factory user. By using Expatica Date, you agree:

  * To be bound by Expatica Dating and Dating Factory terms and conditions (<http://netherlandsdating.expatica.com/terms>).
  * That your Expatica registration information can be transmitted to Dating Factory to facilitate your automatic registration and login to the Dating Factory service.
  * That your membership details, including photos, can be stored, used, transferred or made obtainable past the expiration date of your membership, either by Expatica or World Dating Partners.

If you have questions about the use of the Expatica Date powered by Dating Factory, please contact: <http://netherlandsdating.expatica.com/contacts>.

## Surveys

Occasionally Expatica conducts user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any information about specific individuals with any third party.

## Contests

Expatica sometimes offers contests in which certain personal information is required for registration, for purposes of verifying the entrants’ identities and notifying the winners. If a third party is administering the contest, this information will need to be disclosed to that third party.

## Additional questions

If you have any further questions, please do not hesitate to contact our User Service Department.

Expatica.com reserves the right to modify this policy at any time without prior notice.
